KHOI HUYNH

SUMMARY

I'm currently an MBA student wrapping up his studies. I have 3 years of product management experience, working on B2C e-commerce SaaS apps & Insurance-tech. Before that, I was a developer working on many products including health tech, banking, case management systems, and other client-facing products. Having worked & studied in multiple countries I bring an adaptive & battle-forged mindset with excellent communication skills to the table.

SKILLS & TOOLS

RESTful API · B2C SaaS · Postman ·

Product Management ·

Technical Expertise · Market Research ·

Stakeholder Management .

Business Knowledge •

Priority Management · UI/UX Principals ·

Excellent Comminication · Interpret Data ·

 ${\sf Negotiation} \cdot {\sf Documentation} \cdot {\sf JIRA} \cdot \\$

Asana · Agile Scrum · Figma ·

English / Vietnamese/ French

LANGUAGES

English	Native	•••••
Vietnamese	Proficient	•••••
French	Intermediate	

VOLUNTEERING

Dat Viet Charity Association

www.datvietcharity.org 2013 - Ongoing

Perspective Charity

www.perspectivecharity.org 2020 - Ongoing

Product Manager

EXPERIENCE

Judge.me

Product Manager

06/2021 - 05/2022 HCMC & London

Reported to the Senior PM and CEO in a startup environment. Lead a B2C SaaS app that allows +200k merchants to build trust with social proof from user-generated content.

- Applied customer, market, and internal data to make data-driven decisions to grow monthly installs by 15% in Q3-2021 by restructuring app listing, speed optimizations, and new features for underserved customer needs.
- Implemented an announcement banner to increase engagement and awareness with customers by sharing tips, announcements, and promotions. This resulted in more subscription conversions which grew revenue by 6%.
- Successfully forged strategic partnerships with Google, Shopify, and SquareSpace increasing revenue streams by utilizing exclusive deals and partnership programs.
 Expanded target audience reach by 3.5m users, adding functionality and driving growth.
- Conducted competitive analysis to determine competitive position. The insights on feature comparison, third-party integrations, and customer journey allowed for the creation of a strategic roadmap to maintain the number 1 app in Shopify.
- Worked with cross-functional teams to revamp UI/UX to decrease churn rate by 3% in Q3-2021 by applying A/B tests, highlighting core features in the onboarding process, and using tools such as Hotjar's heatmap to determine pain points.

Technical Product Manager

10/2019 - 06/2021

Yas Digital

HCMC & London

Built an insurance-tech app from ideation to MVP in 3 months coordinating a team of 2, which quickly grew to 8 within the year. Transforming and disrupting the insurance industry by launching innovative insurance products to market.

- Implemented a loyalty points system that increased retention rate by ~10% by allowing
 users to earn loyalty points through interactions with features and processes in the app
 such as; reading blogs, completing onboarding steps, and purchases.
- Discovered low-performing metrics for sales of insurance products. Increased the
 conversion rate by 22% by optimizing UI/UX elements to reduce friction of the customer
 journey where high bounce rates and low usage times were found.
- Tested APIs with Postman, wrote technical specs for creating APIs, and conducted technical research on third-party integrations by reading API documentation to see if they were technically compatible and also followed Hong Kong's insurance data laws. Suitable integrations saved significant development time of up to 95%.
- Maintained and owned the product backlog by creating user stories and prioritizing tasks based on priority frameworks such as RICE and MoSCoW, as well as having transparent communication with stakeholders and team members about scope and product vision alignment to ensure deadlines had a 90% delivery rate.

Software Application Developer	09/2018 - 02/2019
i-Sight	Ottawa, Canada
Software Developer Intern	05/2018 - 09/2018
Sarana Yukti Bandhana (SYB) Online	Jakarta, Indonesia
Software Developer / Associate Project Manager	12/2016 - 04/2018
TelASK Technologies	Ottawa, Canada

EDUCATION

Master of Business Administration (MBA)	2021 - Ongoing
Western Sydney University (HCMC Campus)	HCMC, Vietnam

Bachelor of Computer Science Honors, Management and Business Systems

Carleton University

Ottawa, Canada

2014 - 2019

- Graduated with Honors
- Co-founder and VP of the Carleton University Photography Club (CUPC)